JONATHAN ARMSTRONG DATA ANALYST

Summary

I am a data analyst specializing in public education. I have experience wrangling, cleaning, analyzing, and modeling data to suite needs district and campus needs while applying in-depth domain knowledge based on hands on experience in the classroom.

Employment

Southwestern Adventist University Keene, Texas Data Analyst Jan. 2021 to Current, Jan. 2021 to Current

- -Gathered data via various campus channels
- -Performed exploratory analysis to provide insight and recommendations to the university
- -Generated and presented regular reports to OIER Committee

Bay City ISD Lead Teacher Elem Bay City, Texas July 2017 to July 2021

- -Utilized Organization Health Improvement data to develop campus improvement plan
- -Analyzed behavioral data on Multi-Tiered System of Support team to create and monitor campus behavior management
- -Monitored and visualized student academic data regularly
- -Supported team in implementation of classroom technology
- -Lead and organized team meetings to establish grade-level long and short term goals.

Projects

Python and Google Slides: Peripheral Recommendations to Improve District STAAR Meets Score

Gathered and cleaned TEA snapshot district data for state of Texas in 2018. Used exploratory data analysis to gather insight on actionable features and the relationship of those features to STAAR data. Used machine learning to predict STAAR scores for 2020 data as well as offer suggestions to two districts on how to raise the number of students meeting the STAAR in their area.

Volunteering

Cleburne ISD · Volunteer Data Analyst Cleburne Texas

Current

Worked with assistant superintendent to perform analysis and draw insights on pain points for the district

Contact

- jonathan.alan.armstrong@gmail.com
- https://github.com/jonarms/Portfolio
- **\$179336841**

in www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanarmstrong-data

Education

Springboard Data Aug. 2021 Science Career to Feb. Track 2021

Portfolio Projects:

https://github.com/jonarms/STAAR_Re 6-month intensive course in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL.

Southwestern 2009 to Adventist University 2013

BS Communication 2013

Skills

LANGUAGES: PYTHON (PANDAS, NUMPY, SEABORN, SCIKIT), SQL

STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: DESCRIPTIVE AND INFERENTIAL STATISTICS, REGRESSION MODELING, HYPOTHESIS TESTING